Good morning everyone and welcome
ma to data-driven event today it's great to be in new york on
...in...in fact the last time I was in new york
was for our devices launch and it's great to be back here for none of
those super important milestone for us at microsoft with our data
technologies and platform launch today it's a huge business for us but,
more than that what is important is the broad impact that transformed
...it's...our customers and here we are to talk about a lot of the technology
and the impact in fact I travel around the world and
talked to lots of customers' partners?
Others government leaders it's
clear the digital transformation of every part of
society and economy is top of mind to these leaders.
And, then when you in fact people talk about this fourth industrial
...just like the first three with steam
...and information technology it had a pretty broad impact
in the way we live the way we work the way we entertain ourselves
the way we communicate and now when we talk about this for
the industrial revolution with digital technology we're talking...having perhaps even
a broader deeper impact on all those aspects of our lives?
it's interesting to sort of look back and sort of say what is it that causes that transform,
transform of impact.
What is the confluence of circumstances that brings that transformation
about?
This definitely technology
the technology that connects everything there is not a place
a person or a thing that is not connected.
All of these connected.
Entities create lots and lots of data
...one estimate is that we already have something like ten z...bytes of data and then by twenty,
twenty we will have fifty...bytes of data.
And, the question then of course is how is all this
data being used there is a new form of computing.
That is also simultaneously developing called cloud computing this is a way
the brain storage compute network in
a completely different way so that you can deal with this level and the scale of data
and turn that and process that and can word it?
So, it's that circuit it's that new beginning
all of a set of technologies that are
...involving having everything connected generating lots of data
and having a new form of computing that can in fact process all of that
data that's bringing forth this digital transformation.
And, we think that...digital transformations impact
...the very beginning of it it's in the years
and the decades to calm that we will truly understand and realize the
benefits it's also going to be a tumultuous period of change.
For us in our businesses and how we navigate that is going
to be at a premium?
And, to asks the question...course is what is microsoft
doing in data in fact the way we start is to think of data
paths this new electricity because I think that's the best.
Way to characterize the our of data and it's
transformed apollo it's more than just data by itself it
is the ability to unlock from data the
...and intelligence that is going to create that...it's
moving from having lots of data to creating.
Predictive our
an analytical our inside of every organization that's what the
fourth industrial revolution is all about and that's what we're focused on in fact
we draw inspiration from everything we do at microsoft from
our mission our mission at microsoft is to empower every
person and every organization on the planet to achievable these
are just a set of words for us in fact it's a guide.
That reminds us every day about the choices we make whether it be
a customer interaction or a product design decision so that
we are doing things that we can uniquely
do and contributed as a company and more importantly that
...useful and impactful for our customers so when you look at it through that lens.
What we're trying to get done in data comes to focus,
for example, we as an company focus a
lot on both people and organizations
we deeply believe in the our of institutions companies
non-profits public sector we think that institutions
...what build economies and societies and of course institutions
are built by people so that connection between how people
come together and how institutions tribe using technologies
front-and-center to us so when we talk about data that notion of being able to take
lots of data and convert it into better decisions better
judgment better intelligence is the most important
thing that we think about
as we build-up products we also think about it from a global scale?
Up in fact a round data but at the very beginning
of even understanding what are the frameworks of law what
are the regulations because...gotta be enduring principles that you
have to navigate and keep constant.
For example, the set of security how
...want to keep data secure how is it going to be private how is
it going to be transparent to the users in terms of what the data is being useful
and then compliance these are the enjoying principles on a worldwide
basis not just in one jurisdiction not one-in-one country but
on a worldwide basis that you have to really think through not just
after the fact but in the design decisions of the products that you use in the products that you built.
And, lastly.
More than anything else it's that notion
of achievement for us success does not...
In launching products in fact I sort of
a joke internally that we should not have launch events we should only have
customers successive events because it's really not a marker
of any progress if all we do is launch technology and release
products it is only useful when it is being transformed.
By our customers in fact we're...
Microsoft is really about digital technology from each one
of our customers and we want to provide the broad platforms that
helps create that that's at the center of our mission this
transformation is well on its way you get these early signs every
a block or every error has the harbinger of what's
...to calm what is the way this transformation will play out can
forecasted if you will by looking at some of the early customers, for example,
in our case we're very inspired by some of the business transformation stories take
piston crop which is an elevated company out of the
heart of germany has over a million elevators they
were now able to connect all of those million machine elevators into connected
smart elevators transform the business model from having.
Reactive repairs on elevators
to proactive up diamond la as new service contracts.
So, that is not just a bunch of digital services they created but it's a fundamental
shift in the business model you'll hear later from johnson controls how
...are going through this transformation...built building control systems for a
long-time but now they're all connected and, now because of that connection in
their analytical capabilities...transforming not only the sla that they can
...to their customers but more importantly energy consumption which
is obviously of super important thing not only for their customers but for us as a society.
You take a look at prewar which is a fascinating story it's a
start-up out of london in fact they went and took all
of the underground air raid shelters from world war two and converted
them into new urban farming sentence.
And, again, why...they able to do that they were able to do that
...because of y ot sensors and the ability to do farming
in agriculture and improve its productivity in a completely new way?
You look at even...whether.
They've always had rather data and they've had consumer products.
now they're not only taking a historical weather and their predictive our in terms of weather
forecasts and making it available to other business so if you
...manufacturer...retailer think about both
your supply chain and your inventory efficiency.
Because of this new capability that you have to be able to use weather predictions as a way
to predict what may happen in terms of consumer behavior and product sell true.
You see document hitchcock completely transform what personalized care would
They're building in systems where they're not only collect data with the
...and privacy and all of the compliance requirements
but to transform it to better health outcomes for their patients remote
monitoring personalized care are just new digital
products and services that they're creating so this transformation
is very broad and there is industrial, industrial
company after company that's going through this.
In fact I like to think
about even microsoft is changing because of data.
Even this morning when I got up I went to my our by reports to look at the
usage stats across all of our services from last night and it's not something I
used to do even a couple of years ago but now if you sort of look at any
one at microsoft the very nature of how we build
products how we instrument them to be able to take data from
them and use that to make better decisions about what comes next
was blind.
Faith in our own conviction
...completely changed how we think about product development in fact I
would say it's this data signs and design are two things
that are changing how we think about even product development at the core.
How we measure success?
Ceos we're all responsible for showing up every
quarter especially for people in new york and talk about our success.
When we know that success that we talk about on those quarterly calls are lagging
indicators
not leading indicators and the real trick is how are we
as organizational an organization leaders in touch?
With those leading indicators of success.
Some of our best people
inside are people who are defining those needing indicate a metrics.
So, that we know that this has predictive our of future success.
So, it's having this very broad impact on how
we build products how we measure success and how we
even engage our employees...one of the products that we
have at microsoft is called organizational analytics and the idea
here is to be able to give individuals at microsoft or
anyone who uses office three six five the our to reason over
their most precious commodity which is time
so they can use that time wisely?
And, the fact that I can just like how I get my health data
from my band I can in fact look at the number of meetings I'm having how many how much of
that time is being spent with external customershow much of it is being
...on real issues that matter all of that intelligence in fact shapes
how allocate my time going forward so those just examples of what is real
for meaning in my daily life in terms of how you in
calculating these data products inside of our own behaviors actions and culture?
And, today what you'll hear about is a lot of the technology...
broad deep digital data platform.
This platform.
Is going to help every business become a software business a
data business and intelligence business that's our vision we want them to be able to
take not only their data collected in large amounts storage
secure me process it but convert
it into insights and intelligence that analytical and predictive our?
We not only we also want to
keep everyone not just in the
it industry but in every sector with the skills
around data literacy which I think are going to be key.
For jobs of the future competitiveness of the future.
So, that's what the rest of today is all about it's about technology but
it's in technology in your hands in our customers' hands and how it is
setting the stage for their own transformation?
Their own digital transformation and that's what you want to hear about the rest of
the day and I'm really excited because this business is a very critical business and as I
said the very...for me it is that
...our that this technology has the
fact that this speaks to the very core of the microsoft mission of how
we can bring digital technology that empowers every person
in every organization on the planet to achieve more and today is a very
big milestone in that process thank you very much and at this point I'll have scott got three
who leads our data platform and cloud platform teams to come up on stage.